Preliminary Guide to the Office of Fellowships and Scholarships, School of Business and Public Management records, 1951-1989 RG0098
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Office of Fellowships and Scholarships, School of Business and Public Management records
1951-1989
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Office of Fellowships and Scholarships
RG0098
9 Linear Feet
Materials in this collection include the Wolcott Foundation brochures and annual reports, student files, Scottish Rite brochures (1962-1985) reports and statistics for the Scottish Rite Fellowships, (1951-1987). The collection ranges in date from 1951 to 1989.
Restrictions on Access
Series 1 through 3 are closed to research for 25 years from date of record creation.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition data is unknown.
Historical or Biographical Note
In 1928, the School was founded on the idea, new for its time, that business and government might become partners in promoting national prosperity and international development. Beginning with a $1 million endowment from the League of Masonic Clubs, The George Washington University (GW) President Cloyd H. Marvin established what was known as the School of Government, with degree programs that integrated business and politics on the national and international levels.
In the years following World War II, change came rapidly. In 1960, the School was renamed the School of Government, Business, and International Affairs. Then, in 1966, President Lloyd H. Elliott split its faculties into a new School of Government and Business Administration (SGBA) and a School of International Affairs -- which today bears President Elliott's name. The SGBA was renamed the School of Business and Public Management (SBPM) in 1990. In 2004, it became the School of Business.
Throughout its history, GW School of Business has attracted some of the nation's most outstanding leaders from academia, government, and the business world. In 1992, F. David Fowler, a managing partner of KPMG (Klynveld Peat Marwick Goerdeler), became dean of the school. During his tenure, he dedicated himself to educating a generation of effective managers.
Dean Fowler was succeeded in July 1998 by Susan M. Phillips. A former member of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, Dean Phillips brings to the School her expertise in such specializations as derivatives, bank supervision, and financial management. She also continues to serve as a professor in the School's finance department.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include the Wolcott Foundation brochures and annual reports, student files, Scottish Rite brochures (1962-1985) reports and statistics for the Scottish Rite Fellowships, (1951-1987). The collection ranges in date from 1951 to 1989.
Collection Organization
Organized into three series: School of Government and Business Administration (SGBA), School of Business and Public Management, and Wolcott Foundation and Scottish Rite.
Statistics; Students; George Washington University. School of Business; Elliott, Lloyd H.; Marvin, Cloyd Heck; George Washington University; Scottish Rite (Masonic order)
- School of Government and Business Administration (SGBA), 1951-1987; RG0098 Series 1; 0.5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  The series contains brochures, reports, and statistics for Scottish Rite Fellowships. They range in date from 1951 to 1987.
  Formerly ACC#58
  - Wolcott Fellows Directory, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Wolcott Fellowship Directory, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Wolcott Foundation Invitation, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Wolcott Scholars Alumni Directory, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Wolcott Fellowship Program, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Wolcott Scholarship Program, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Scottish Rite Fellows Alumni Directory, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Kentucky Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - District of Columbia Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Scottish Rite Fellowship Directory, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hyundai Scholarship Program, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Charter of the Wolcott Alumni Association of Washington, DC, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Printout of data on the Scottish Rite funding of the Fellowship Program, 1957-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Wolcott Foundation and George Washington University, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "High Twelve...Masonry In Action" Article, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Wolcott Foundation and Scottish Rite, 1962-1985; RG0098 Series 3; 2 Linear feet
  This series is a collection of Wolcott Foundation brochures and annual reports, student files, and Scottish Rite brochures. They range in date from 1962 to 1985.
  Formerly ACC#93
  - Wolcott Foundation Fellowship Program: Student files, 1962-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Trustee: Loran Bartley
  - Wolcott brochures and directories, 1971-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scottish Rite brochures and directories, 1968-1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Wolcott Foundation annual reports, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Article: "What is Hi-Twelve?", undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Director's Fund, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Director's Fund, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Director's Fund, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Beijing Institute of Foreign Trade, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Jin Hai Lin
  - Thaddeus and Mary Jean Linder Program: Student files, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Chivas Regal Young Entrepreneur Award, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Beatrice Scholarship, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Institute of Certified Public Accountants, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trustees of Wolcott Foundation, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Picture
  - Scottish Rite Fellows, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Wolcott Fellows, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- School of Business and Public Management (SBPM), 1951-1989; RG0098 Series 2; 6.5 Linear feet (Box 6)
  This series is a collection of Scottish Rite fellowships, student files, photographs, and candidate resumes. They range in date from 1951 to 1989.
  Formerly ACC#79
  - Comparative Tution Rates, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Hail to the Joint Chiefs", undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Louisiana Scottish Rite Fellowships - Report of President Marvin, 09/05/1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Scottish Rite Fellowship Program (General) Concerning All States, Southern Jurisdiction, 1951-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alabama Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alabama, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alaska, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arizona, 1966-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arkansas, 1966-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - California, 1967-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Orient of China (Winter Park), 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Canal Zone, 1966-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - District of Columbia Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - District of Columbia, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Colorado, 1965-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Florida, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Florida Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Georgia Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Hawaii, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Idaho, 1966-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Iowa, 1967-1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Iran, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Japan and Korea, 1977-1985 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Kansas, 1965-1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Kentucky Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Kentucky, 1979-1987 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Louisiana Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Krause and Diele, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Louisiana, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Maryland Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Minnesota, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Minnesota Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Mississippi, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Mississippi Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Missouri, 1966-1983 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Montana Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - New Mexico Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - North Carolina Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - North Dakota, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Oregon, 1967-1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Oklahoma, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Philippines Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    EMPTY
  - South Dakota Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Puerto Rico, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Taiwan Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Tennesee, 1966-1978 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Texas, 1967-1981 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Utah, 1967-1981 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Virginia, 1967-1983 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Washington Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Washington, 1977-1989 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - West Virginia Scottish Rite Fellowship Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - West Virginia, 1977-1985 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Wyoming, 1967-1982 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Maryland, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Scottish Rite Stipend Receipts, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Senior Certificates, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Henry C. Clausen, 33 degree Sovereign Grand Commander, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Weekly Wage Account 121, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Scottish Rite Fellowship Program - Changes, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Scottish Rite - General, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - C. Fred Kleinknecht, 1972-1982 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Student Files - Abel, Gregory through Burnett, Robert, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Student Files - Burris, James through Keith, Karla, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Student Files - Keller, Robert through Trosch, Louis, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Student Files - Tucker, Joseph through Zwick, Jack, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Ben Burdetsk: New Dean, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    FILE MISSING
  - Misc. Search Committee Materials, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Candidate's Interview Schedules and Resumes, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Candidate's Resumes and Correspondences, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Search Committee Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Photos: Scottish Rite Fellows, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Photos: Henry C. Clausen, Covereign Grand Commander of the Ancient and Accepted Scottish Rite of Free Masonry, Southern Jurisdiction, USA, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Photos: Grand Commander's Luncheon, 12/06/1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Photos: James S. Burris, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Photos: Grand Commander's Luncheon, Louisiana Fellows, 09/21/1965 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Photos: Grand Commander's Luncheon, Luther Smith, 10/1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Photos: Annual Luncheon Honoring Scottish Rite Fellows, 12/02/1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Fellowships, 1992-2005; Series 4
  - Scholarships and fellowships, 1992-2005; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - Cambridge scholarships, 1992-1994; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 4)